

<u>kevintayah@gmail.com</u>

2843 W Girard Ave, Philadelphia, 19130, USA

**** 267-546-7901

Profile

I love building software that are elegant, concise, and most importantly get the job done. In my past 3 years of experience, I worked on multiple projects, many in the MERN stack. I found myself wearing multiple hats to fulfill company needs, from scrum master to a developer to interviewing potential employees. Sometimes, more than just being a software developer, the need for adaptable team members is what keeps servers running.

Education

BS in Computer Science, Drexel University, Philadelphia

September 2016 — June 2021

Concentration in AI, Data Structures, and Algorithms

Links

LinkedIn Website Github

Skills

HTML/CSS/JavaScript React
React Native Redux
Svelte Node.js
Python C++
Rust Elixir
MongoDB Postgres
Git FFMPEG

Employment History

VP of Engineering, Wolf Financial, Philadelphia, PA

March 2021 — Present

- Worked closely with designers and board members to manage tasks in an Agile fashion and develop timelines and task lists
- Communicated with external partners to coordinate development efforts, with various, software, including <u>Alpaca</u>
- Interviewed 20+ people to help expand the team
- Mentored 3 junior developers, training them in the company's best practices of app development, as well as React Native, Redux, and other useful developer tools
- Continued Full-Stack Engineer responsibilities

Full-Stack Software Engineer, Wolf Financial, Philadelphia, PA

June 2020 — March 2021

- Developed the Wolf application, utilizing React Native, Node.js, MongoDB.
- Utilized APIs and tools including Plaid, Alpaca, Finnhub, Firebase, FFMPEG, Jest, AWS Lambda, and AWS Elastic Beanstalk.
- Implemented many social media-type features, like a basic video editing interface for "stories", a reply-thread system similar to Reddit, and multiple ways of displaying stock related data

Helped Wolf acquire angel investments totaling up to \$750,000 and grow it's user base by 400%

Software Developer Contractor

Internships

Software Engineer, Nuix, Conshohocken, PA

September 2019 — April 2020

- Worked on Investigate, a data search and visualization tool for unprocessed data, that used React, Redux, Java Spring and a mono-repo that utilized Storybook for Nuix's custom UI framework.
- Worked closely with UI/UX designers to deliver business oriented solutions.
- Worked on Discover, a data processing application that facilitates the usage with Investigate and other Nuix products. Utilized a similar tech stack as Investigate.

Software Developer, KieranTimberlake, Philadelphia, PA

September 2018 — April 2019

- Worked on automated unit, integration, and acceptance testing for Roast, a workplace comfort survey app that allows a company assess, manage, and improve comfort inside the workplace.
- Worked with MVC language Ember.js, and the Qunit testing framework.
- Overhauled and optimized <u>Pointelist</u>, a high density temperature and humidity sensor network that is configured to collect data on spaces and places.
- Utilized a Raspberry PI running a Node.js application to manage the collection and sending of data periodically while insuring data safety.
- Developed and improved a visualization tool for Roast.

Software Engineer, SAP America, Newtown Square, PA

September 2017 — April 2018

- Overhauled, documented, and fully tested internal full-stack software using SAP UI5 and Java while utilizing enterprise design techniques.
- Worked with a small team to create a JPA based back-end and API.
- Effectively communicated and worked closely with an international development team using Agile methods.

Projects

Drexel Weekend Warriors Club Website

June 2019 — June 2021

A full-stack_website made for the <u>Weekend Warriors</u> at Drexel University. This website features a headless CMS and a method of signing up for an event through a form with the ability to prevent double signups from a single user. Up to 500 users have signed up through this website. This project used Next.js and Redux for the front-end and the Strapi framework for the back-end. It is hosted on an AWS EC2 instance, but no longer maintained. Code available on Github

Stripe Invoicer

November 2021 — December 2021

An Electron based app built for a friend to assist in automatically billing customer based on a csv file and any stripe API key. API key is hashed and stored for future use, and any recurring customers are stored using a SQLite. Code avaliable on Github

Languages

English, Arabic

Hobbies

Rock climbing, hiking, camping, slack-lining, and any outdoor activities